Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit and today I am presenting to you
the comparison of the top plans of the industry, a combination of ULIP and term plan. You
will be happy to know which plan will be best for you. You can understand from this video
that in which plan your premium will be less, in which plan maturity
will be more, in which plan you will get more riders, in which plan
the premium payment is better for you, in which policy term is less for you, in which the education
criteria is less for you, in which the income criteria will be best for you, so
I have compared all the criteria. If you like my video, then like,
share and subscribe. My channel is Anil Rajpurohit FFFS. Today I
am presenting to you three best plans of the industry, one is Tata, this
is a Param Rakshak, Param Raksha Karma Solution, the second is ICC's product and Green Plane for you
and the third product for you is HDFC Life Insurance's Smart Protest. I
have also made individual videos of these three plans
for you on my YouTube channel, now go there and If you can see in details
, then the comparison of all three is here for you. First of all, you
see the features, there is an entry in the policy, its proposer's entry, how much money is required, so
a person from 18 to 60 years can purchase all three policies, talk about
when the policy matures, then the customer needs money for it, so the minimum
money required is 48 years from now, maximum 85 and 100 years, like Tata, this is a Param
Lakshya, in this the minimum increase is from 48 to maximum 100 years, if we talk about
ICC, then the minimum maturity should be 48 years from now,
the policy should mature and the maximum is 90 years from now and the smart product which
is HDFC's plan has a maximum and minimum maturity of 43 and 100 years, talk about
the policy,
if you want to take a policy term of 40 years,
in ICC it is 30 years and 40 years for you, but
from 30 to 40 You can select 31, 32, 33, 34, 35 in this way 3940
but you can do 30 or 40 in between, you cannot do 31, 32
in HDFC also, if you want you can take 31, 32, 33 in this way. Now if we talk
about the premium payment term in all the three policies, then in Tata, the Param Akshar Plane,
the premium payment in it is on Five Air, Ten Air, 12 Air Limited and Regular, but
in ICC, that is Fight You 12, that means 56789, 10, 11, 12, we
can select the premium payment for this also and you can select the regular premium payment.
If we talk about the minimum insurance tax, then in all the three policies, there
should be a minimum insurance tax of 50 lakhs, the maximum insurance tax is very good in Tata,
here you can take insurance of more than one crore, if your income
is good,
then you can take insurance of more than one crore also, but
in ICC, this limit No, here you can take a maximum of one crore only.
There are many riders in both the policies, different things are given here, but
the rough comparison that I have done for you is the Accidental Death and Accidental
Total and Permanent Disabilities Rider and with the normal
insurance policy. So the maximum policy term of these two riders is that
in Tata and ICC, they provide coverage up to 85 years, but in HDFC, the maximum rider
is only up to 75 years. Income on Accident Rider. This rider
is not available in Tata and ICC, but it is available in this plan of HDFC Life Insurance,
where you will get 1% of the insurance policy every month. Suppose you
have taken this Accidental Death and Disabilities policy of Rs 1 crore, and
if there is no death here, but there is a disability,
there is a permanent disability,
then 1% of that, ₹ 1 lakh, will come every month for the next 10 years in this rider.
You will get this, it is available in all three because
if you like this policy, then the charger is refunded in all these three policies. After 10 years,
if there is mortality charge, then both Tata, ICC and HDFC, all these three companies
give you double mortality charge back after the 10th year. ICC gives you three times mortality back after 25 years
and HDFC gives you three times mortality back
after the third year. As for the refund of such charges, then
in the policies of all the three companies, you get premium allocation charge refund. If we
talk about top up premium in this policy, then in all these three policies, you have
been given the option of top up. If you want, you can avail your benefit by paying additional premium.
You can increase your fund. Tata
gives 11 funds to invest in your policy, ICC gives you 18 funds to invest and HDFC Life
Insurance gives you five funds to invest. All these
three companies also give you different strategies to invest.
Talking about parcel withdrawal, it is the most important. If you ever need money,
if you need liquidity and you do not want to take a loan, then you
can do parcel withdrawal. You get particular facilities in all three policies.
In Tata, after 5 years, you can now do parcel withdrawal from this policy. There is no cap, no limit here.
You can do cap only 10-20% but in ICC
you will be able to parcel only 20% of the fund value and there is no such capping of funds in HDFC as well.
Talking about
the option of increasing or decreasing the insurance tax in the policy, is it available or not? This option is available
in HDFC Life's smart product plan. This
type of option is not available in ICC and Tata. Which of these three
plans has such a capital guarantee where the investment you have made, say your premium is ₹1 lakh, if you
have paid 10 lakh rupees in 10 years, then the fund value should never be less than 10 lakh, is there
such a capital guarantee or not, then you will get this option in HDFC,
there is no capital guarantee option in Tata, let's talk about the most
important thing, before taking the policy, you must keep in mind whether you
are eligible for this policy or not, as per the income and education criteria,
can you take this policy or not, if we talk about Tata, there
are three-four options in Param Lakshya, you can keep Param Lakshya, Param Plus Param Rakshak
3, there are many four-five variants of Param Akshar, there are different
criteria of income and education in all of these, the income should be minimum 3 lakh rupees, first of all, if you
are not giving income proof for this, then it is okay, you are giving declaration, meaning you are telling in the proposal form
that your income is three lakh, second minimum this should be the maximum if If it is as per 7.5 lakhs
, then your education criteria will also be available even if you are 5th pass,
but if your income is not up to 7:30 lakhs, then your education criteria will also
be minimum 12th pass or graduate. Talking about ICC, ICC
requires an income of three lakhs and should be at least 12th pass. If
you are just 12th pass, you will not get this policy, or if you have 10 plus diploma, then you will get it. So
here also
you will not get this for taking education. Talking about HDFC, there
is no income and education criteria here. If you have failed 5th, you can still take your policy,
but your declared income should be according to your undertaking.
For example, till the age of 35, if you
get 25 times insurance tax or 20 * more insurance, then you should have a declared income of two or 2.5 lakhs.
For this, you do not need to provide income proof. 18
According to the guidelines, if we talk about critical illness, critical hospital rider, then
in Tata you get a critical illness rider of approximately 40 critical illnesses.
For this you will have to pay a separate premium.
It will come in the solution of Param Rakshak Plus. However, you do not get such a critical illness rider in ICC.
HDFC has 19 critical illness riders. Talking about cancer rider, it is
a separate personal insurance for cancer care for this illness. It only protects cancer.
The premium is quite cheap. It is available with HDFC.
[Music]
They keep an insurance of one crore. There is a rider of one crore for accident death and
there is also a tax of ₹1 crore for accident total and permanent disabilities. So, in Tata,
their premium will be for the basic insurance of 1 crore, 91000 743.
The premium for accident death rider will be 1000070. The rider for permanent disabilities will cost
₹6.80. Premium mega total your premium will be
₹17893 and your maturity will come after 40 years, that will be 4796, if we talk about ICC's
premium which is ₹1 lakh, basic
lakh 41320, about 40 lakh from Tata,
if we talk about HDFC, then the premium is class 1733 and here you
will get maturity of 81 lakh if ​​we see the illustration of 8%, on the basis of that I have created this equipment,
here there can be market apps and doctor, the maturity coming in this
can be both less or more than this, but let's take a person of 45 years instead of 35 years,
from the same 10 years premium payment term policy term 40 years normal
tax of one crore, one crore if an accident happens, then disability cover of one crore so here
The premium of Tata is Rs 2 lakh 12228 and
you will get a fan value of 1.1 crore on your maturity, the same ICC will give you
Rs 2 lakh for free
on maturity, there will be a difference of
70 lakh in premium, the premium of HDFC
is around 19 crore, if you have HDFC's phone
, where should you go, so you see, the tax of Tata will
be of 50, but HDFC's will be
around
2 lakh, the benefit of 1184000 will be Rs 1 lakh 86000
for 10 years, so the difference comes to 18-19 lakh rupees
and it depends on the maturity because the premium will definitely
be less, so now you have to decide whether you want to go for a lower premium or a higher one,
you have to go for a higher maturity, the difference is going to be a lot,
there is no education criteria in HDFC, whereas in other companies, 12th is the standard and in this way Tata If you want to take Param
Rakshak, if your income is 7 1/2 lakhs,
then you will get it. If you are a graduate and your salary income is 3.5 lakhs, but here if you are a small businessman and
you have it and even if you are 5th pass, you
can also get it. If you want to take it in ICC, if you match the criteria and you are 12th
pass and have an income of 3 lakhs, then you are getting more fan value very well.
Here I have taken HDFC in permanent disabilities with double star.
Here, as I explained in the beginning about permanent disabilities,
you will not get one crore at once, you will get one lakh rupees every month for the next 10 years, even then
it will be 1.2 crores. Okay, there is an income option in both the other options, in Tata and
ICC, you get lump sum together that if someone dies in an accident,
the company will give 2 crores, all the three companies will give two, but if there is no death in an accident and
disability occurs, then Tata will give 1 crore, ICC will give 1 crore, but HDFC ₹1
lakh If you want to understand all these three videos in individual details, then
all three videos are available on my YouTube channel Anil Rajbhar Triple FS. I
have shared its screenshot here with you. So this is a very good plan. In today's time,
you need both more insurance tax and maturity. In case of
your early death, then one crore rupees will be sufficient for your family. If nothing
happens to you, if you have an income of 665, then you can utilize the money a lot for retirement.
If you invest up to 2.5 lakh in ULIP plan, the maturity that comes
will be tax free. You can also avail the tax benefit of ATC up to ₹1.5 lakh.
If you like my video, then like, share, subscribe and
if you want to purchase this plan, then also you can contact me
on double 9 0 9403412. If you want more information, if you do it tomorrow, then it will not be free. IT bill will be
chargeable. Thank you, so match